# **Adam Faraj**

faraj.9798@gmail.com, (336) 430-6178

An experienced, passionate front end software developer. Building applications using JavaScript including modular and object-oriented best practices on both the front and back end, primarily in Angular, React, React Native, and NodeJS. Participates in prototyping, design and development, content generation, coding, deployment, documentation, CI/CD, and DevOps best practices. Comfortable with the use of version control, automated unit testing, and AWS services, including S3, Cognito, Lambda, Amplify, Route53, and DynamoDB. Always furthering knowledge in related technologies to stay on top of industry standards and best practices.

# **Experience**

# Front End Web Developer - Market America (June 2019 - Present)

- Build e-commerce websites primarily using the JavaScript ecosystem with a ColdFusion back end.
- Responsible for transitioning from legacy systems to Docker.
- Responsible for building and minifying code using Gulp.
- Edit, maintain, and deploy projects using Agile methodology.
- Responsible for the creation of styleguides for company wide use.
- Responsible for code reviews, merges, and git-flow using Bitbucket.
- Training resource for junior developers and onboarding resource for new hires.
- Responsible for deployment automation and scripts using Blueprint.

# Web Consultant – Rural Sourcing Inc. (May 2018 - June 2019)

- Lead front end developer on application using Angular, AWS Lambda, and NodeJS.
  - Successful delivery resulted in the client being bought by a major company.
- Built a web application using Angular, AngularJS, CSS/SASS, JavaScript, MongoDB, AWS, and NodeJS.
  - Successful delivery resulted in substantial growth in the client's customer base.
- Edited, maintained, and reviewed code using Bitbucket.
- Deployed projects using Netlify.
- Developed applications using Agile methodology.
- Directly communicated with clients to gather requirements and set goals for desired results.
- Mentored associate web developers with web development and best practices.

### **Web Developer** – Adam Faraj Solutions (March 2015 - Present)

- Created jourdainfisher.com for comedian/actor/writer Jourdain Fisher using AWS tools and React.
- Developed a customer facing store, maintained infrastructure, and modernized code and architecture.

### **Junior Web Developer (Contractor)** – Lexo (January 2015 - March 2015)

• Built a landing page as part of a small team using BEM and helped bring art concepts to implementation with clean and robust HTML, CSS, and JS.

### Education

### BS, Biology (Pre-Medical) – University of North Carolina at Greensboro, 2013

• Relevant coursework: Physics I / II, and Calculus I / II / III

#### **Interests & Activities**

• Assistant teaches web development and internet fundamentals at the local public library. Continuous education in software related technologies, such as SQL Essentials, Java Basics, and Python Basics.